<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.firebasebuilduploader.android</id>
    <name>Firebase Co-Pilot Build Uploader</name>
    <vendor email="hardil.undavia@gmail.com">Hardil Undavia</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <b>Firebase Co-Pilot: Build Uploader</b> — The all-in-one Firebase App Distribution tool for Android developers.<br/><br/>

        Build, sign, and distribute your Android app to Firebase App Distribution without ever leaving Android Studio.
        The plugin handles everything: flavor detection, APK assembly, release signing, upload, release notes, and
        tester-group distribution — all from a single tool window.<br/><br/>

        <b>✦ Core Features</b>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Auto Flavor Detection</b> — Scans <code>build.gradle</code> / <code>build.gradle.kts</code> for
                <code>productFlavors</code> (both Groovy and KTS DSLs). Falls back to a
                <code>firebasecopilot-flavors.json</code> file when Gradle parsing is not possible.</li>
            <li><b>Build Type Selection</b> — Supports Debug, Release, and any custom build types defined in your project.</li>
            <li><b>One-Click Build &amp; Deploy</b> — Runs <code>./gradlew :app:assembleFLAVORBUILDTYPE</code>, locates
                the generated APK, and uploads it to Firebase — all in a single click.</li>
            <li><b>Build Only Mode</b> — Assemble an APK locally without uploading.</li>
            <li><b>Firebase Auth via Service Account</b> — Authenticates using a Service Account JSON file.
                No manual token management or CLI setup required.</li>
            <li><b>Release Notes</b> — Choose from saved templates or write custom notes. Notes are attached
                to the Firebase release automatically.</li>
            <li><b>Tester Group Distribution</b> — Reads <code>groups</code> from the
                <code>firebaseAppDistribution { }</code> block in your build.gradle and distributes the
                release to those groups automatically after upload.</li>
            <li><b>Live Build Log</b> — Streams Gradle output directly in the tool window panel.</li>
            <li><b>Persistent Settings</b> — Remembers your last App ID, service account path, and up to
                20 saved release note templates across IDE restarts.</li>
            <li><b>Recent Deployments History</b> — Tracks the last 10 deployments with timestamps, flavors,
                build types, and Firebase Console links.</li>
            <li><b>Auto Project Sync</b> — Re-scans flavors and build types automatically whenever Gradle
                syncs, keeping the UI always up to date.</li>
        </ul>

        <b>✦ Signing Configuration (New in v2.0)</b>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Release Signing Warning</b> — Detects missing signing config when "release" build type is
                selected and prompts you to configure it before building.</li>
            <li><b>Signing Config Wizard</b> — Generate a signingConfigs block and inject it into
                <code>build.gradle</code> / <code>build.gradle.kts</code> automatically.</li>
            <li><b>Create New Keystore</b> — Generate a brand-new <code>.jks</code> / <code>.p12</code>
                keystore via <code>keytool</code> with a guided form (alias, passwords, certificate DN,
                validity period) — no terminal required.</li>
            <li><b>Use Existing Keystore</b> — Point to an existing keystore file and the plugin writes
                <code>keystore.properties</code> and injects the Gradle signing block for you.</li>
            <li><b>Secure by Default</b> — Credentials are stored in <code>keystore.properties</code>
                (never hardcoded in build.gradle) and the plugin automatically adds keystore files and
                property files to <code>.gitignore</code>.</li>
            <li><b>Supports Groovy &amp; KTS</b> — Signing config injection works for both
                <code>build.gradle</code> (Groovy) and <code>build.gradle.kts</code> (Kotlin Script).</li>
        </ul>

        <b>✦ How to open</b><br/>
        <i>Build → Firebase Co-Pilot: Build Uploader</i> or press <code>Alt+Shift+B</code>.
        The panel docks to the right sidebar.<br/><br/>

        <b>✦ Requirements</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Android Studio (Hedgehog or later recommended)</li>
            <li>A Firebase project with App Distribution enabled</li>
            <li>A Service Account JSON with the <i>Firebase App Distribution Admin</i> IAM role</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <b>2.0.2</b> — Marketplace publishing &amp; validation fixes<br/>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix: Service Account JSON validation</b> — Re-selecting a file (including the same path after the file is restored) now updates the validation label and icons correctly; clearing the path hides success/error icons.</li>
            <li><b>Fix: Plugin archive extraction</b> — Plugin ZIP is now built with STORED compression so JetBrains Marketplace can extract and verify the archive.</li>
            <li><b>Fix: Android Studio–only compatibility</b> — Declared <code>com.intellij.modules.androidstudio</code> and Gradle plugin dependencies so the plugin is verified for Android Studio, not plain IntelliJ IDEA.</li>
            <li><b>Fix: IDE version range</b> — Added explicit <code>since-build</code> / <code>until-build</code> for Android Studio 2025.1 through 2026.2.</li>
        </ul>

        <b>2.0.1</b> — Platform compatibility &amp; security hardening<br/>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix: JetBrains Marketplace compatibility warnings</b> — Migrated away from deprecated IntelliJ Platform APIs scheduled for removal in Android Studio 2025.x / 2026.x (file chooser, Gradle sync listener, and project refresh APIs).</li>
            <li><b>Fix: Dependency vulnerabilities</b> — Upgraded Google Auth Library and pinned transitive dependencies to resolve CVE-2023-2976 (Guava) and WS-2019-0379 (Apache Commons Codec).</li>
            <li><b>Improvement: Compile SDK</b> — Plugin is now built against Android Studio 2025.1 Platform APIs for forward compatibility with current IDE releases.</li>
            <li><b>No functional changes</b> — Build, deploy, signing wizard, keystore creation, and Firebase upload behavior are unchanged from v2.0.0.</li>
        </ul>

        <b>2.0.0</b> — Signed APK &amp; Signing Configuration Support<br/>
        <ul>
            <li><b>New: Release Signing Wizard</b> — Detects missing signing config when the "release" build
                type is selected and shows a clickable inline warning. Opens a guided dialog to apply signing
                configuration directly from the panel.</li>
            <li><b>New: Create Keystore dialog</b> — Generate a new <code>.jks</code> / <code>.p12</code>
                keystore via keytool without leaving Android Studio. Supports full certificate DN, custom
                alias, separate key/store passwords, and configurable validity period.</li>
            <li><b>New: Gradle signing config injection</b> — Automatically writes
                <code>keystore.properties</code> and injects a <code>signingConfigs</code> block into
                <code>build.gradle</code> or <code>build.gradle.kts</code>. Safe to re-apply — replaces
                any previously injected block.</li>
            <li><b>New: Auto .gitignore update</b> — Keystore files and property files are added to
                <code>.gitignore</code> automatically to prevent accidental credential commits.</li>
            <li><b>New: Tester group auto-distribution</b> — Reads <code>groups</code> from the
                <code>firebaseAppDistribution { }</code> block and distributes releases to those groups
                after every upload.</li>
            <li><b>Fix: Duplicate APK from wrong flavor</b> — APK discovery is now scoped strictly to the
                selected flavor + build type directory; stale APKs from other flavors are never used.</li>
            <li><b>Fix: Gradle abort on missing Firebase task</b> — The <code>-x appDistributionUpload</code>
                exclusion flag is now only passed when the Firebase Gradle plugin is actually present,
                preventing "Task not found" errors on plain projects.</li>
            <li><b>Fix: Correct Firebase Console URL</b> — The console link now uses the URL returned
                directly by the Firebase API instead of a reconstructed one.</li>
            <li><b>Improvement: Auto-refresh on Gradle sync</b> — Flavor and build type combos update
                automatically after every Gradle sync without requiring a manual refresh.</li>
        </ul>

        <b>1.0.0</b> — Initial release<br/>
        <ul>
            <li>Auto flavor detection from build.gradle / build.gradle.kts</li>
            <li>Build type selection with flavor combos</li>
            <li>One-click Build &amp; Deploy to Firebase App Distribution</li>
            <li>Service Account JSON authentication</li>
            <li>Release notes templates with persistent history</li>
            <li>Live Gradle build log in the tool window</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.androidstudio</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.java</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.android</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.plugins.gradle</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow
                id="Firebase Co-Pilot: Build Uploader"
                anchor="right"
                factoryClass="com.firebasebuilduploader.ui.FirebaseCoPilotToolWindowFactory"
                icon="/icons/40.png"
        />

        <applicationService
                serviceInterface="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.FirebaseCoPilotSettingsService"
                serviceImplementation="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.FirebaseCoPilotSettingsService"
        />

        <projectService
                serviceInterface="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.GradleFlavorDetectorService"
                serviceImplementation="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.GradleFlavorDetectorService"
        />

        <projectService
                serviceInterface="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.BuildService"
                serviceImplementation="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.BuildService"
        />

        <projectService
                serviceInterface="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.FirebaseDistributionService"
                serviceImplementation="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.FirebaseDistributionService"
        />

        <projectService
                serviceImplementation="com.firebasebuilduploader.services.SigningConfigService"
        />
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action
                id="FirebaseCoPilot.OpenPanel"
                class="com.firebasebuilduploader.actions.OpenFirebaseCoPilotAction"
                text="Firebase Co-Pilot: Build Uploader"
                description="Open Firebase Co-Pilot: Build Uploader panel to build, sign, and distribute your Android app"
                icon="/icons/14.png"
        >
            <add-to-group group-id="BuildMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="MainToolBar" anchor="last"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="alt shift B"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>